先生 原型已经通过了每项测试
The prototype has passed every test, sir.
它可以启动了
It's working.
我不认为“启动”
I hardly think "working"
是恰当说法
is the correct word.
那仅适用于机器身上
That would apply only to machines.
对不起 我应该说
I'm sorry. I should say,
“它活过来了”
"It's alive."
它能听到我吗
Can it hear me?
可能仍处于昏迷中
It might still be in shock.
但是 大脑已经被焊接到外骨骼上了
Bear in mind the brain has been welded to the exoskeleton.
金属外壳
Skin of metal.
以及长生不老之身
And a body that will never age or die.
我妒忌它
I envy it.
你认识我吗
Do you know me?
回答我
Answer.
你认识我吗
Do you know me?
你是约翰·卢密克
You are John Lumic.
我的孩子
My child.
记住这一天 肯德里克博士
Mark this day, Dr Kendrick.
我们受到祝福
We are blessed.
然而事情还没完 先生
Well, it's not quite over yet, sir.
我们需要日内瓦的许可
We need Geneva's approval.
技术上讲 这是一种新型生命
Technically, this is a new form of life,
这违反了生物章程
and that contravenes the Bio-Convention.
这需要经过他们批准
They'd need to ratify this.
他们会反对我
And they will refuse me.
无论如何 我们必须通知他们
Nonetheless, we need to tell them.
那么如果我不去呢
And if I don't?
那么对不起 先生 但这是我的职责
Well, I'm sorry, sir, but it's my duty.
我必须去通知他们
I shall have to inform them.
你从坟墓里要怎么通知他们呢
And how will you do that from beyond the grave?
我不是很明白
I don't quite understand.
杀了他
Kill him.
船长
Captain.
是的 先生
Yes, sir?
通知所有船员
Inform all staff
我们有新的目的地了
we have a new destination.
设定航线
Set sail
向大不列颠进发
for Great Britain!
那个有双大眼睛的“大嚼族”女士
...and that weird munchkin lady with the big eyes.
还记得她看你的眼神吗
You remember the way she looked at you?
然后她张大嘴 就喷火了
Then she opens her mouth and fire comes out!
我想我都快笑累了
I thought I was gonna get frazzled!
上一秒她还好好的站在那儿 下一秒她就…
Yeah, one minute she's standing there, the next minute,
那是哪里的事 发生什么了
Where was that? What happened?
那是在…那是…
Oh, it was on this...er,
在一个星球上的事 小行星
planet thing. Asteroid.
说来话长 你得身临其境才行
It's a long story. You had to be there.
你按着那个干什么
What are you doing that for?
是你叫我按的
'Cause you told me to.
什么时候
When was that?
大概半小时之前
About half an hour ago.
你现在可以松手了
Urn... You can let go now.
多久前我就可以松手了呢
Well, how long's it been since I could've stopped?
十分钟前
Ten minutes.
二十…
Twenty.
二十九分钟
Twenty nine.
你把我忘记了
You just forgot me!
不不不 我只是…
No, no, no, I was just...
我只是…我在校准
I was calibrating.
我只是… 不 我很清楚自己在做什么
I know exactly what I'm doing.
发生了什么
What's happened?
时间漩涡 它不见了
The time vortex. It's gone.
那不可能 它刚刚不见了
That's impossible. It's just gone!
自己抓稳了 我们要坠毁了
Brace yourselves! We're gonna crash!
大家都还好吗 洛斯 米奇
Everyone all right? Rose? Mickey?
我没事 还好 抱歉
I'm fine, I'm okay, sorry, yeah.
她死了
She's dead.
塔迪斯死了
The Tardis is dead.
你能修好它
You can fix it.
没有什么可修的了
There's nothing to fix.
她死掉了
She's perished.
宇宙中最后一个塔迪斯 灭绝了
The last Tardis in the universe. Extinct.
我们能找人帮忙 不是吗
We can get help, yeah?
去哪儿找
Where from?
我们着陆了 我们肯定在某个地方
Well, we've landed. We've got to be somewhere.
我们从漩涡中掉出来
We fell out of the vortex,
穿过空洞 进入了无意义空间
through the void, into nothingness.
我们处在某种虚无空间
We're in some sort of no place.
寂静领域
The Silent Realm.
失落的维度
The Lost Dimension.
或者也叫做伦敦
Otherwise known as London.
伦敦 英格兰 地球
London, England, Earth!
等等
Hold on...
2月1号 是今年的
It's the 1st of February. This year.
冲得也不是很远 是吧
Not exactly far ?ung, is it?
那这就是伦敦
So this is London?
是的
Yup.
你的城市
Your city?
就是那个
That's the one.
和我们离开时一样
just as we left it?
非常对
Bang on.
而且还有齐柏林飞艇
And that includes the zeppelins?
见鬼
What the hell?
真漂亮
That's beautiful.
这是伦敦在举行国际飞艇节
Okay, so it's London with a big International Zeppelin Festival.
这不是你的世界
This is not your world.
但既然日期是同一天的话…
But if the date's the same...
是平行的 对吗
It's parallel, right?
我说得对吗
Am I right?
一个有着齐柏林飞艇的平行世界
Like a parallel Earth only they've got zeppelins?
我说得对吗 对了 是吧
Am I right? I'm right, aren't I?
肯定是了
Must be.
一个平行世界…
A parallel world where...
拜托 你在电影里看过的
Come on, you've seen it on films.
就像我们世界的一个变体
Like an alternative to our world
那里什么都一样
where everything is the same
就是有些许不同 比如
but a little different. Like,
我不知道 交通灯是蓝色
I don't know, traffic lights are blue,
或者托尼·布莱尔从没当选
Tony Blair never got elected...
或者他还活着
And he's still alive.
一个平行世界 我爸爸还活着
A parallel world where my dad's still alive.
别看 洛斯 甚至想都别想
Don't look at it, Rose. Don't even think about it.
这不是你的世界
This is not your world.
他是我爸爸 而且...
He's my dad. And...
相信我 没错的
Trust me on this.
噢 真奇怪
Oh, that's weird.
但他是真实的…
But he's real...
相信我 没错的
Trust me on this.
他成功了
He's a success.
他总是爱策划这些蠢蠢的方案
He was always planning these daft little schemes,
健康食品 饮料之类的
health food drinks and stuff.
每个人都说没用
Everyone said they were useless.
但他做到了
But he did it.
洛斯 如果相信过我
Rose. If you ever trusted me,
那现在请听我的
Then, listen to me now.
不要再看他了
Stop looking at him.
你父亲已经死了
Your father's dead.
在你六个月大的时候死了
He died when you were six months old.
那不是你的皮特
That is not your Pete.
他是另一个皮特
That is a Pete.
我们都知道 他有自己的杰琪 自己的洛斯
For all we know he's got his own Jackie. His own Rose.
他自己的女儿 是别人 而不是你
His own daughter who is someone else, but not you.
你不能见他
You can't see him.
永远不能
Not ever.
相信我 没错的
Trust me on this.
你好
Hello?
亲爱的
Sweetheart?
是我
Only me.
倒霉鬼来了
Oh, the bad penny.
这是你的主意吗
Was this your idea?
不要抵赖
Don't deny it.
到处都是你的指纹
It's got your fingerprints all over it.
相信我 没错的
"Trust me on this."
相信你是吧
Oh, I can trust you all right.
信你个大头鬼
Trust you to cock it up.
我做错什么了
What have I done now?
自己看看
Have a look.
那有什么问题
What's wrong with that?
40岁 上面写着40岁
40! It says 40.
你确实是40岁啊
You are 40.
我不想昭告天下 好吗
I don't want the whole world telling, do I?
今晚你有一个派对
You're having a party tonight!
我39岁生日
My 39th!
我的官方传记上说
My official biography said
我和小库珀·古丁是同一天出生的
I was born on the same day as small Cuba Gooding was .
所以说我是39岁 谢谢
And that makes me 39, thank you very much.
洛斯 到这儿来 洛斯
Rose. Come here. Rose.
这是办公室的姑娘们送的
These are from the girls in the office.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
我和来自冰岛的雕刻家有约
I've got hand sculpted arrangements
来自雷克雅未克的维罗妮卡
by Veronica of Reykjavik
而你的秘书却把车开到了修理站
and your secretary stopped off at a garage.
我看还是算了吧
I don't think so.
如果你要送礼物
And if you're giving out presents,
说好的飞艇呢
where's my zeppelin?
别人家个个都有飞艇
Everyone else has got one.
洛斯
Rose!
过来 洛斯
Come on, Rose!
我打赌你根本没注意到 是吧
Bet you didn't even notice, did you?
特别礼物
Special delivery.
今天才送来的
Got sent round today.
卢密克先生送的生日礼物
Birthday present from Mr Lumic,
最新款
latest model.
镶了钻石
Diamond studded.
能接收到委内瑞拉的信号
Pick up signals from Venezuela.
你要从委内瑞拉接收信号干嘛
Why would you want to pick up signals from Venezuela?
不知道 但现在我能试试了
Well, I don't know, but now I can find out!
看在上帝的份 她在哪里 洛斯
For God's sake, where is she? Rose!
今晚之前她得好好洗个澡
She needs a good bath before tonight
不然又会叫个不停的
or she's gonna be honking. Rose!
洛斯 到妈妈这里来
Come to mummy,
过来
come on!
你来了 亲爱的
there you are, my darling.
卢密克先生
Mr Lumic!
杰琪刚还向你道谢 你真好
Jackie was just saying thank you. That's very kind of you.
那些耳机是手工制作的
Those Ear Pods are handmade.
告诉她小心些
Tell her to take care.
当然了 我会的
Course I will. Course I will.
不知你今晚能来参加我们的聚会吗
I don't suppose you'll be joining us tonight, for the party?
我们会很荣幸的
We'd be very honoured.
下面世界的人可以聚会
The world below can party.
而我们还有工作要做
Some of us have work to do.
我的计划领先了 皮特
My plans have advanced, Peter.
总统已经答应了一个决定
The President has promised a decision.
我还在飞行中
I'm flying in now.
我们下午五点降落
We will be at the airstrip by 5:00.
好的
Right.
我答应了今晚要帮我妻子的忙
It's just that I promised I'd help the wife out tonight.
英国总统都能抽出时间参加会议
If the President of Great Britain can make this meeting,
那么你也能
then so can you.
我不知道 他老婆又不是杰琪 对吧
He's not married to Jackie, is he?
五点钟 泰勒先生
5:00, Mr Tyler.
值得载入史册的日子
A famous day!
声纹认证 约翰·卢密克
Voice print access, John Lumic.
启动耳机控制
Initiate Ear Pod override.
目标：杰奎琳·泰勒
Subject: Jacqueline Tyler.
激活
Activate.
下载
Download.
泰勒住所
Tyler residence.
二月一号
February the 1st.
给我今晚的安全信息
Give me security arrangements for tonight,
各种密码 加密服务
passwords, encryption services.
现在 恢复
And restore.
谢谢了 泰勒女士
Thank you, Mrs Tyler.
激活图像连接
Activate picturelink.
奎恩先生
Mr Crane.
卢密克先生
Mr Lumic.
事情进展比我预期的还快
Events are moving faster than I anticipated.
我需要更多人员
I need extra staff.
很好 先生
Very good, sir.
我要继续招募人手了
I shall go on a recruitment drive.
支援她
Back her up.
我告诉过你要盯住她
I told you to keep an eye on her.
她没事的
She's all right.
她四处乱逛
She goes wandering off...
平行世界就像诱人的姜饼屋
A parallel world, it's like a gingerbread house.
各种诱惑在呼唤着她
All those temptations calling her.
噢 只是洛斯而是吗
Oh! So it's just Rose, then?
没有东西会诱惑我
Nothing out there to tempt me?
我不知道 我不能每件事都操心
Well, I don't know. I can't worry about everything!
如果能让这玩意…
If I could just get this thing to...
起作用了吗
Did that help?
是的
Yes.
疼吗
Did that hurt?
是的 嗷
Yes. Ow.
这对英国来说是个好消息
...and it's good news for Great Britain
约翰·卢密克返回了他的祖国
as John Lumic returns to the country of his birth.
卢密克先生 高硬度金属的发明者
Mr Lumic, the inventor of High Content metal,
他否认了关于身体问题的流言
has denied allegations of ill health.
我们都是血肉之躯
We're all flesh and blood,
是大脑使我们成为人类
but the brain is what makes us human.
现在我的头脑比任何时候都有创造力
And my mind is more creative than ever.
随着赛博企业股票翻倍
With shares in Cybus Industries doubling in price,
卢密克先生已经承诺…
Mr Lumic has pledged...
另一消息…
In other news.
火炬木研究所发表了一研究 声称…
The Torchwood Institute has published a study claiming that...
我们不应该来这里的
We're not meant to be here.
塔迪斯从宇宙汲取能量 但不是这个宇宙
The Tardis draws its power from the universe but it's the wrong universe.
就像在汽油发动机中灌入柴油
It's like diesel in a petrol engine.
但我在动画片里看过
But I've seen it in comics,
他们在不同的平行世界中穿梭
people go hopping from one alternative world to another.
好像挺容易的
It's easy!
真实世界不一样
Not in the real world.
过去是很容易的
Used to be easy.
那时时间领主还能照顾着一切
When the Time Lords kept their eye on everything,
你能在不同的世界穿来穿去
you could pop between realities,
还能准时回家喝茶
home in time for tea.
然后他们死了 把这些一同带走了
Then they died and took it all with them.
现实之墙关闭了 世界封闭了
The walls of reality closed. The worlds were sealed.
一切都变得不那么友善
Everything became that bit less kind.
那我们怎么到这儿来的
Then how did we get here?
我不知道
I don't know.
意外
Accident.
本来是不可能的 现在我们被困住了
Should've been impossible, now we're trapped.
那是什么
What's that?
什么
What?
那个 那里 那是个倒影吗
That there. Is that a reflection?
是一道光
It's a light!
是吗 是不是光
Is it? Is that a light?
我觉得那是一道光
I think that's a light.
正是我们所需要的
That's all we need.
我们有能源了
We've got power!
米奇 我们有能源了
Mickey, we've got power!
先生们
Gentlemen!
请注意
I beg your attention!
圣诞提前到来了
Christmas has come early
都来过圣诞吧
so come and get it!
啊 闻一闻 同志们
Oh, smell that, comrades!
汉堡和薯条
Burgers and chips!
豆子和香肠
Sausage and beans!
猪肉 鸡肉
Pork, chicken
还有香浓的热茶
and hot sweet tea.
都是免费的
All for free!
不要去
Don't go!
但那里有食物
But there's food.
你们都能吃 不用给钱的
All you can eat, free of charge!
别光站在那里
Don't just stand there.
大吃特吃吧
Fill your faces with pasties...
他们在说谎
They're lying
哦  你说的轻松
Oh. It's easy for you to say.
你上次挨饿是什么时候
When did you last starve?
所有那些消失在街道上的人
All those people disappearing off the streets.
已经持续几个月了
It's been going on for months.
是他们
It's them.
他们会把你带走
They‘ re taking you away.
做什么
What for?
做实验
Experiments.
但赶快哦 慈善团体不提供住宿哦...
我太饿了
I'm so hungry.
所以快趁热享用吧
So come and get it while it's hot!
就是这样 好先生
That's it, kind sir,
进来吃大餐啦
get in there and fill your face!
好好享受 兄弟
Feast yourself, brother,
好好享受
feast yourself.
你在干什么
What are you doing!
把他们带走
Take them away.
不 不  救命
No! No! Help!
它是活的
It's alive!
那是什么
What is it?
什么都不是
Nothing.
它很小
It's tiny.
这只是一个微不足道的小能量块
It's one of those insignificant little power cells
从来没人注意到它
that no one ever bothers about
而它仍然顽强的活着
and it's clinging on to life!
它还剩少量的现实物质躲在里面
It's got one little ounce of reality, tucked away inside.
足够带我们回家吗
Enough to get us home?
还不够
Not yet.
我得给它充充电
I need to charge it up.
我们可以出去把它接到高压线上
We could go outside and lash it up to the national grid.
那不是同类型的能量
Wrong sort of energy.
它需要来自我们宇宙的能量
It's got to come from our universe.
但我们什么都没有
But we don't have anything.
还有我
There's me.
我刚刚给出了10年的寿命
I just gave away 10 years of my life.
每一秒都值得
Worth every second.
它快要熄灭了 没问题吗
It's going out. Is that okay?
它在充电循环中
It's on a recharging cycle.
它会循环回来 充好能量
It'll loop round, power back up
然后很快就能带我们回家
and be ready to take us home
24小时以内
Oh! in 24 hours.
那我们能在这平行世界待24小时了
So that gives us 24 hours on a parallel world?
上岸休假吧
Shore leave.
只要我们一直保持低调
So long as we keep our heads down,
容易 没问题
easy, no problem.
我们去告诉她
Let's go and tell her.
终于找到你了
There you are!
没问题吧
It's all right,
没人鼓掌吗 我修好它了
no applause, I fixed it.
24小时后 我们就能飞回到现实世界
24 hours and then we're ?ying back to reality.
这是什么
What is it?
我的电话连接上了
My phone connected.
这里有赛博网络 连上我的手机了
There's this Cybus network. It finds your phone.
让我连上了互联网
It gave me internet access.
洛斯 不管上面说什么 这不是你的世界
Rose, whatever it says, this is the wrong world.
我并不存在
I don't exist.
什么意思
What do you mean?
这里没有洛斯泰勒  我从没出生过
There's no Rose Tyler. I was never born.
有我爸爸皮特 有杰琪
There's Pete, my dad, and Jackie.
他仍然娶了妈妈
He still married Mum
但是他们从没有孩子
but they never had kids.
把电话给我
Give me that phone.
他们很有钱
They're rich.
他们有房子
They've got a house and
也有车 他们想要的都有
cars and everything they want.
但他们没有我
But they haven't got me.
我要去见他们
I've got to see them.
你不能
You can't.
我只是想见见他们
I just want to see them.
我不能让你去
I can't let you.
你说有24小时
You just said 24 hours.
你不能做他们的女儿
You can't become their daughter.
这样是行不通的 米奇 告诉她
That's not the way it works. Mickey, tell her.
24小时吗
24 hours, yeah?
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
我想做什么都行
Well, I can do what I want.
我有地址和其它信息
I've got the address and everything.
你们两个都待着别动  洛斯 回来
Stay where you are! Both of you! Rose, come back!
米奇 马上回到这里来
Mickey, come back here! Right now!
我只想看看他们
I just want to see them.
我也有些事要看一看
Yeah, I've got things to see and all.
想看什么
Like what?
你对我的事一无所知 是吧
You don't know anything about me, do you?
总是只关洛斯的事 我总是多余的
It's always about Rose. I'm just a spare part.
对不起 我得走了
I'm sorry, I've got to go.
走吧
Go on, then.
没其他选择了 不是吗
There's no choice, is there?
你只能追上我们其中一个
You can only chase after one of us
那永远不会是我 对吧
and it's never gonna be me, is it?
24小时之内回来
Back here. 24 hours.
好的
Yeah.
除非我找到更好的东西
If I haven't found something better.
泰勒先生
Mr Tyler,
发生了什么 不能等到今晚吗
what's the matter couldn't wait until tonight?
总统先生 很荣幸见到你
Mr President. Honoured.
我在进行一个快速紧张的计划
I'm on the fast-track programme.
赛博企业并购了我的公司
Cybus Industries have bought up my company
所以现在我也是该公司的一分子
so I'm part of the firm now.
甚至有人说他们收买了我们的政府
Some people say they've bought my government.
我从没听任何人这样说过
I've never heard anybody say that.
没有
Never.
这点你可以相信我
You can trust me on this.
我喝过你们公司的饮料 那种维铁饮料
I tried your drink, that Vitex stuff.
尝起来像汽水
It tastes like pop.
没错 就是汽水
Well, it is pop.
你把健康食品饮料卖给一个病态的社会来挣钱
You've made money by selling a health food drink to a sick world.
不太像平时的乔的作风 不是吗
Not quite the ordinary Joe you appear to be, are you?
他还真喜欢让我们等
He does like to keep us waiting.
但告诉我
But tell me,
你有绝好机会观察约翰·卢密克
you've had a chance to observe John Lumic more than most.
你有什么看法
What's your opinion?
要我说 他很精明 一如既往的精明
He's very sharp, I'd say, sharp as ever.
很聪明的人 可以说是天才
Very clever man. Brilliant, in fact.
那你不觉得他是疯了
Then you don't think he's insane?
我不会用这个词语来形容
It's not the word I would've used, no.
我明白了
I see.
我能过去吗
Am I all right to go past?
是的 没问题
Yeah. No bother.
宵禁10点才开始
Curfew doesn't start till 10:00.
这里有宵禁
There's a curfew?
当然了
Course there is.
你住哪儿的 老兄
Where you been living, mate?
和那些有钱人在上面住
Up there with the toffs?
我也想啊
I wish.
再见
See you.
米奇的母亲忙不过来
Mickey's mum just couldn't cope.
他爸爸照顾过一阵子 然后又溜走了
His dad hung around for a while, but then he just sort of wandered off.
他是被奶奶带大的
He was brought up by his gran.
她是个伟大的女人
She was such a great woman.
天哪 她过去常常打他
God, she used to slap him!
但是后来她死了
But then she died.
她绊倒了 从楼梯上摔下来
She tripped and fell down the stairs.
大概有5年了 我当时还然在上学
It was about five years ago now. I was still in school.
我从来都不知道
I never knew.
你从来没问过
Well, you never asked.
你从没提起过
You never said.
那是米奇
That's Mickey.
我觉得…
I suppose...
我们都太想当然的对他了
we just take him for granted.
你认为他的奶奶还活着吗
Do you think she's still alive? His gran?
有可能
Could be.
如我所说 平行世界 诱人的姜饼屋
Like I said, parallel world, gingerbread house.
我们必须尽快离开这里
We need to get out of here as fast as we can.
他们都在做什么
What are they all doing?
他们停住了
They've stopped.
是听筒
It's the ear pieces.
就像是蓝牙连接
Like Bluetooth attachments
只不过连接的是人
but everyone's connected together.
传到我电话上来了
It's on my phone.
是自动的 你看 正在下载
It's automatic. Look, it's downloading.
他们都在接收这个
Is this what they're all getting?
新闻 国际新闻 体育 天气
News, international news, sport, weather.
他们直接接收
They get it direct.
下载到他们的大脑里
Downloaded right into their heads.
电视时间表 彩票中奖号码
TV schedules, lottery numbers.
每个人都共享同样的信息
Everyone shares the same information.
“每日下载 由赛博企业提供”
Daily download, published by Cybus Industries.
你们这些人 你们太沉迷了
You lot, you're obsessed.
你们会不惜一切进行最新的升级
You'll do anything for the latest upgrade.
喂 他们不是我们那边的人
Oi, they're not my lot.
不同的世界 记得吗
Different world, remember?
但离你的世界不是很远 这地方只是平行的而已
It's not so far off your world. This place is only parallel.
噢 看看那个
Oh, look at that.
赛博企业
Cybus Industries,
拥有英国的所有公司
owners of just about every company in Britain,
包括维铁公司
including Vitex.
皮特·泰勒先生与此事大有关系
Mr Pete Tyler's very well connected.
好吧 我认输 一起去见见他吧
Okay, I give up. Let's go and see him.
谁在那里
Who's that there?
你是谁
Who is it?
我知道你在那里
I know you're there.
真为你感到羞耻 骗老太婆
Shame on you, tricking an old lady.
我已经没什么东西给你偷了
I've got nothing worth stealing.
别以为我会消失
And don't think I'm gonna disappear.
你别想带走我
You're not gonna take me!
嘿
Hi.
是你吗
Is that you?
是我 我回来了
It's me. I came home.
瑞奇
Ricky!
我是米奇
It's Mickey.
我知道我自己孙子的名字
I know my own grandson's name.
是瑞奇 过来吧
It's Ricky. Now come here.
好吧 我是瑞奇
Okay, I'm Ricky.
我当然是 瑞奇 就是我
Of course I am. Ricky, that's me.
你这个蠢小子
You stupid boy!
你去哪里了
Where've you been?
不要打我了
Stop hitting me!
已经过了好久了
It's been days and days.
我一直听说人们从街道上消失的事情
I keep hearing all these stories, people disappearing off the street.
下载里也没什么官方消息
There's nothing official on the download
但到处是这事的谣传和私语
but there are all these rumors and whispers.
我以为他们把你带走了
I thought they'd gone and disappeared you.
我让你修一下楼梯上的地毯
That carpet on the stairs, I told you to get it fixed.
你会…
You're gonna...
摔断自己的脖子
fall and break your neck.
那你帮我修好它
Well, you get it fixed for me!
很早之前我就应该做的
I should've done it way back.
我猜我就是这么没用
I guess I'm just kind of useless.
我从没这么说过
Now, I never said that.
但我是这么想的
I am, though.
对不起 奶奶 真对不起
And I'm sorry, Gran. I'm so sorry.
别那么说
Don't talk like that.
知道你现在需要什么吗
Do you know what you need?
好好坐下
A nice sit down
然后喝杯茶
and a cup of tea.
你有时间吗
You got time?
为了你 我有全世界所有的时间
For you, I've got all the time in the world.
你只是嘴上说说罢了
you say that but it's all talk.
你那些新朋友
It's those new friends of yours.
我不信任他们
I don't trust them.
什么朋友
What friends are they?
别装你不知道
Don't pretend you don't know.
有人看到了
You've been seen.
昌太太告诉我的
Mrs Chan told me.
慌慌张张地开着一辆运货车
Driving about, all helter-skelter, in that van.
那是什么运货车
What Van's that, then?
你知道的
You know full well.
别耍我
Don't play games with me.
马上进来
Get inside.
我到处找你
I've been looking for you everywhere!
瑞奇
Ricky. Ricky!
瑞奇 是你告诉我们的
Ricky, you were the one who told us.
不要联系自己的家人
You don't contact your family
因为那会给他们带来危险
'cause it puts them in danger.
是啊 瑞奇说过
Yeah. Ricky said that.
我当然说过 只是测试而已
Course I did. just testing.
我看见他们了
I saw them.
我把他们录下来了
I taped them.
他们到布莱克修道院周围
They went round Blackfriars
像人贩子那样把流浪汉聚集起来
gathering up the homeless like the Child Catcher.
他们一定带走了四十多人
They must have took four dozen.
运货车的雇佣者是
The vans were hired out to a company
国际电子商品公司
called International Electromatics.
但是我做了一个协议搜索
But I did a protocol search,
结果只是一个空壳公司
turns out that's a dummy company
猜猜谁是幕后主脑
established by guess who?
我不知道 谁
I don't know. Who?
赛博企业
Cybus Industries!
现在我们有证据了
Well, now we've got evidence!
坏消息是他们已经逮捕了瘦子吉米
Bad news is they've arrested Thin Jimmy.
所以就轮到你了
So that just leaves you.
轮到我什么
Leaves me what?
第一啊
The number one.
名单上的头号
Top of the list.
伦敦头号通缉犯
London's most wanted.
好的 很酷
Okay. Cool.
再说一遍
Say that again.
地球上最宝贵的东西就是人类的大脑
The most precious thing on this earth is the human brain
我们却放任其死亡
and yet we allow it to die.
但现在赛博企业找到了完美的方法
But now Cybus Industries has perfected a way
来将大脑永久地存放在
of sustaining the brain indefinitely within
装有独创药品的容器中
a cradle of copyrighted chemicals.
最新的神经研究成果
And the latest advances in synapse research
使得网络神经脉冲能够
allows cyberkinetic impulses
传导到金属外骨骼
to be bonded onto a metal exoskeleton.
这是最终的升级
This is the ultimate upgrade.
是我们通向电脑空间最伟大的一步
Our greatest step into cyberspace.
对不起
I'm sorry,
能不能就此打住
could we stop it there?
不用再向我推销了
I don't need the pitch.
我想我们都知道这次最终升级的条件
I think we all know what this ultimate upgrade entails.
我在这儿告诉你 约翰
And I'm here to tell you, John,
答案是“不”
the answer is no.
我的政府不会给你许可的
My government does not give you permission.
我想任何政府都不会答应的
And I think no government ever will.
我给伦理委员会准备了一份报告
I've prepared a paper for the Ethical Committee.
噢 得了吧
Oh, come on!
这不仅仅是不道德
It's not just unethical,
这是亵渎
it's obscene.
总统先生
Mr President,
我能否作个私人请求
if I might make a personal plea.
我快要死了 先生
I am dying, sir.
我知道这一点
I'm aware of that.
非常抱歉
And I'm very sorry.
没有这个项目 你等于给我判了死刑
Without this project, you have condemned me.
我的发明是整个星球最先进的
My inventions have advanced this whole planet.
你要让这些毁于一旦吗
Would you have all that perish?
约翰 你是个很好的生意人
You're a fine businessman, John.
但你不是上帝
But you're not God.
我真的非常抱歉
I'm really very sorry
但我认为我们应该就此停止
but I think we should end it there.
泰勒先生
Mr Tyler,
今晚再见
I'll see you tonight.
我想我们需要好好喝一杯
I think we could all do with a drink.
卢密克先生
Mr Lumic.
尽管如此
Still,
这又不是世界上唯一的国家
it's not the only country in the world.
还有新德国可以去
There's always New Germany.
这是我的祖国
This is the homeland.
我的出生地
My birthplace.
你可以离开了
You may leave.
谢谢 先生
Thank you, sir.
奎恩先生
Mr Crane!
随时候命 先生
Ready and waiting, sir.
做好控制工作没有
Did the override work?
还需要好好调整一下
Well, it needs a bit of fine tuning.
由于时间紧迫 我们还不是很精确 但是
We weren't exactly delicate given the rush. But,
是的 是的 他们都能动
yeah, yeah, it's all working.
我已经测试好系统了 先生
I've been testing the system, sir.
这些已经在移植处理中
They've grafted on a treat, these have.
让您安心一点
Given a little persuasion.
请您看仔细了 先生
If you'd care to observe, sir.
向右转
Turn to the right.
向左转
And back to the left.
你玩得很高兴吗 奎恩先生
Are you having fun, Mr Crane?
不不 不是的 先生
No, no, not at all, sir, no.
只是…这个难以抗拒
It's just... Well, it's irresistible.
赶紧抗拒了然后开始升级
Then resist and start the upgrade.
我们得到许可了吗
Did we get permission?
我听从更高级的法则 老朋友
I am governed by greater laws, old friend.
人的求生权
The right of a man to survive.
现在开始
Now begin!
向左转
turn to the left.
向前走
Forward march.
让我们覆盖这些噪音
Let's cover up that noise.
播放19声道的歌曲
Give us track number 19.
♪ In the jungle The mighty jungle ♪
♪ The lion sleeps tonight ♪
♪ In the jungle,the quiet jungle ♪
♪ A wim-o-weh ♪
灯是开着的 有人在基地里
There's a light on. There's someone inside the base.
穆尔太太 我们有访客
Mrs Moore, we've got visitors.
一、二、三
One, two, three,
走
go!
你究竟在做什么
What the hell are you doing?
你在那里做什么
What are you doing there?
我在这儿做什么
What am I doing here?
我在那儿做什么
What am I doing there?
他们有客人
They've got visitors.
二月一号 妈妈的生日
February the 1st. Mum's birthday.
即使在平行宇宙 她也喜欢派对
Even in a parallel universe, she still loves a party.
皮特·泰勒家的客人名单 我可以看一看
Well, given Pete Tyler's guest list, I wouldn't mind a look.
要进去的话这个办法比较有把握
And there is one guaranteed way of getting inside...
通灵纸片
Psychic Paper
你想变成谁
Who do you want to be?
我们本来能变成任何人
We could've been anyone.
能进来就行 不是吗
It got us in, didn't it?
你有通灵纸片 我们明明可以作为客人
You're in charge of the psychic paper. We could've been guests.
名人 博士爵士 洛斯女爵士
Celebrities. Sir Doctor, Dame Rose.
结果现在成了服务生
And we end up serving.
这些活我在家时做的够多了
I did enough of this back home.
想要调查发生了什么
If you want to know what's going on,
就到厨房做事
work in the kitchen.
据露西所说
According to Lucy,
那边那个男人...
that man over there...
露西是谁
Who's Lucy?
就是端着三文鱼盘子的那个
She's carrying the salmon pinwheels.
哦 那就是露西吗
Oh, that's Lucy, is it?
是的 露西说他是英国的总统
Yeah. Lucy says that is the President of Great Britain.
怎么是总统啊 不是首相吗
What, there's a president, not a prime minister?
看来如此
Seems so.
或者露西就是有点蠢
Or maybe Lucy's just a bit thick.
请注意 谢谢你们
Excuse me, thank you very much.
谢谢 大家请注意
Thank you, if I could have your attention please.
皮特 上去吧
Come on, Pete.
谢谢大家
Thank you very much.
我想说谢谢你们的到来
I'd just like to say thank you to you all for coming
在这个特殊的场合
on this very special occasion.
我妻子的
My wife's...
39岁生日
39th.
我才不相信
Don't believe that,
相信我
Trust me on this.
不多说了 她出场了
And so without any further ado, here she is,
我们的寿星 我可爱的妻子
the birthday girl, my lovely wife,
杰琪·泰勒
Jackie Tyler.
现在我不演讲
Now, I'm not giving a speech,
这是我的派对的闻名之处
that's what my parties are famous for,
不讲工作 不讲政治
no work, no politics.
就只是一些好朋友和大量黑市威士忌
just a few good mates and plenty of black market whisky.
原谅我 总统先生
Pardon me, Mr President.
好的
So, yeah,
大家玩得开心点 好好享受
get on with it. Enjoy! Enjoy.
你不能留下来
You can't stay.
即使有办法告诉他们
Even if there was some way of telling them.
我当然不能
Course I can't.
我妈妈还在家呢 我真正的妈妈
I've still got Mum at home, my real mum.
我不能就这样离开她 是吧
I couldn't just leave her, could I?
只是…
It's just...
他们已经拥有对方了
They've got each other.
妈妈谁也没有
Mum's got no one.
她有你 他们两个没你
She's got you. Those two haven't.
这些不同的世界 没有一个是正确的
All these different worlds, not one of them gets it right.
洛斯
Rose!
我的小宝贝来了
Here's my little girl!
来妈妈这 来妈妈这 好孩子
Come to mummy, come to mummy, yes.
你是不是好孩子啊
Good girl, aren't you!
对不起
Sorry.
第二排现在登机
Platoon 02 now boarding.
别盯着看
Stop staring.
但他们是什么 先生
But what are they, sir?
我说过了 他们是未来
I'm told they're the future.
科技不是很奇妙吗
Ain't technology wonderful?
继续做事 上出租车 启动
Go on, get to the cab, start her up.
先生
Sir.
奎恩先生…准备好了吗
Mr Crane, are we mobile?
正开始上路呢 先生
just about to hit the road, sir.
你呢
And yourself?
我到了 奎恩先生
I'm arriving, Mr Crane.
准备工厂
Prepare the factory.
现在 派他们出去吧 老朋友
Now send them forth, old friend.
伟大事业开始了
Let the good work begin.
他是清白的 没有漏洞
He's clean. No bugs.
但这太离谱了
But this is off the scale.
他是有血有肉的 这是怎么回事
He's flesh and blood. How did that happen?
可能是赛博企业
Well, it could be that Cybus Industries
完善了人类克隆技术
have perfected the science of human cloning.
或者你的老爸有外遇
Or, your father had a bike.
你的名字是米奇 不是瑞奇
And your name's Mickey, not Ricky?
米奇
Mickey.
我的父亲是杰克逊·史密斯
Dad was Jackson Smith,
他曾在克利夫顿广场的钥匙铺工作
used to work at the key cutter's on Clifton Parade.
他去了西班牙 再也没有回来
Went to Spain, never came back.
但那是我老爸
But that's my dad.
所以…
So...
我们是兄弟
we're brothers?
说实话 还能是什么呢
Be fair, what else could it be?
我不知道…
I don't know.
但他并不只是长得像我
But he doesn't just look like me.
而是跟我完全一样
He is exactly the same.
这事肯定有蹊跷 杰克
There's something else going on here, Jake.
你们是什么人呢
So who are you lot?
我们…
We?
我们是传教士
We are the Preachers.
就像圣经里的"绝对真理"
As in "gospel truth".
你看到了没
Do you see?
没有耳机
No Ear Pods.
当世界其余的人从赛博企业下载之时
While the rest of the world downloads from Cybus Industries,
我们是自由的
we have got freedom.
你面前的是伦敦头号通缉犯
You're talking to London's most wanted.
但头号目标是卢密克
But target number one is Lumic
我们准备把他扳倒
and we are going to bring him down.
从你的厨房里
From your kitchen?
你有意见吗
Have you got a problem with that?
不 这是个好厨房
No. It's a good kitchen.
双子星上传了些东西
It's an upload from Gemini.
谁是双子星
Who's Gemini?
货车回来了
The vans are back.
他们正离开巴特西
They are moving out of Battersea.
看上去双子星是对的
Looks like Gemini was right,
卢密克终于要动手了
Lumic's finally making a move.
而我们紧随其后
And we are right behind him.
整理一下 我们要走了
Pack up, we're leaving.
记得她21岁时
I remember her 21st.
在乔治家喝了一品脱苹果酒
Pint of cider in the George.
对不起…要香槟吗
Sorry, sir, champagne?
也好 反正是我的
Might as well, I'm paying for it.
今晚是你的大日子
Big night for you.
是她的
For her.
她还是很开心
Still, she's happy
她应该快乐
Yeah, she should be.
这个聚会很棒
It's a great party.
你真这么想
Do you think?
你可以相信我
You can trust me!
“相信我 没错的”
"You can trust me on this.  -
就是这样 抱歉
"That's it, sorry. Yeah.
那么
So,
你们俩结婚多久了
how long have you two been married?
二十年
20 years.
没有孩子或…
No kids, or...
我们一直搁置着
We kept putting it off.
她说不想毁掉身材
She said she didn't want to spoil her figure.
还不太迟 她才四十岁
It's not too late. She's only 40.
三十九
39.
好吧 三十九
All right, 39.
还是太迟了
It's still too late.
我上个月搬出去了
I moved out last month.
但我们没有对外声张
We're gonna keep it quiet,
你知道的不利于生意
you know. It's bad for business.
为什么我要告诉你这些
Why am I telling you all this?
我们之前没见过 是吧
We haven't met before, have we?
不知道 你看上去有点…
I don't know, you just seem sort of...
什么
What?
我不知道 有点…
I don't know. just sort of...
很对劲
right.
史蒂夫 情况如何
Stevie, how's things?
火炬木那边怎样了
How's it going at Torchwood?
我不知道他们在做什么
I don't know what they're doing,
但看上去这是目标
but this seems to be the target.
大房子 很多钱
Big house, fair bit of money.
现在我们要找到进去的方法
Now we've got to find a way to get in there.
我已经辨认出了地址
I've identified the address,
这属于皮特·泰勒
it belongs to Peter Tyler,
维铁公司的百万富翁
the Vitex millionaire.
皮特·泰勒
Pete Tyler?
他是卢密克的走狗之一
He's listed as one of Lumic's henchmen,
国家的叛徒
a traitor to the state.
但是…
But...
我们得进去
We've got to get in there!
闭嘴 冒牌货 这是我的话
Now shut it, duplicate. That's what I just said.
他们在做什么
What are they doing?
他们到底是什么
What the hell are they?
地球上最宝贵的东西就是人类的大脑
The most precious thing on this earth is the human brain..
泰勒女士 你需要什么吗
Mrs Tyler, is there anything I can get you?
让时间倒流二十年
The last 20 years back.
我能给你一杯香槟
I could manage a glass of champagne.
或者一杯好茶
Or a nice cup of tea?
噢 这个可以
Oh, that'd do me.
我妈妈最喜欢那样了
My mum loves that.
在一整晚后 她从不直接上床
End of a long night, she never goes straight to bed.
她总是醒着等她最后那杯茶
She always stays up just to have that last cup of tea.
哦 我也一样
Oh, I'm the same.
两颗糖
Two sugars.
我也是…
And me.
皮特总是说“你知道…”
And Pete always says, you know...
别管他了
Never mind him.
我刚刚和他聊过
I was talking to him earlier.
他是个不错的人
He's a nice man.
你知道的
You know,
总是我行我素的
a bit of a jack the lad,I suppose,
即使有钱了也一样
even if he has got money.
但他是个不错的人
But he's a good bloke.
比大多数都好
Better than most.
他值得拥有第二次机会的
He's worth a second chance.
你是在评论我的婚姻吗
Are you commenting on my marriage?
不 我只是…
No, I was just...
你以为你是谁  你只是个小工
Who the hell do you think you are? You're staff.
你什么都不是 只是打工的
You're nothing but staff.
你只是个服务生 看在上帝份上
You're just the serving girl for God's sake!
你别想拿到工资了
And you are certainly not getting paid.
竟然敢这样对我说话
Don't you dare talk to me.
这是最终的升级
This is the ultimate upgrade.
我们通向赛博空间最伟大的一步
Our greatest step into cyberspace.
赛博
Cybus.
又发生了
It's happening again.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我见过他们
I've seen them before.
他们是什么
What are they?
赛博人
Cybermen.
卢密克先生
Mr Lumic.
总统先生
Mr President.
我猜现在讨论党会的分解
I suppose a remark about crashing the party
再合适不过了
would be appropriate at this point, sir.
我已经下了禁令
I forbade this.
这些是我的孩子 先生
These are my children, sir.
你要否认我的家庭吗
Would you deny my family?
他们是什么 机器人吗
What are they? Robots?
比那更糟糕
Worse than that.
这些人是谁
Who were these people?
那不重要
It doesn't matter.
他们是人
They're people?
他们曾经是
They were.
直到他们所有的人性被剥夺
Till they had all their humanity taken away.
那是装在金属躯体里的大脑
That's a living brain jammed inside a cybernetic body.
心脏都是钢铁的
With a heart of steel,
所有感情都被移除了
all emotions removed.
为什么要移除感情
Why no emotions?
因为很疼
Because it hurts.
我要求知道 卢密克
I demand to know, Lumic,
这些人到底是谁
these people, who were they?
他们曾是流浪汉 渣滓 和废物
They were homeless and wretched and useless,
直到我拯救了他们
until I saved them,
提升了它们
and elevated them,
给予了他们永恒的生命
and gave them life eternal.
现在 我就把你交给它们了
And now I leave you in their capable hands.
晚安 先生
Good night, sir.
晚安 总统先生
Good night, Mr President.
我们已经升级了
We have been upgraded.
升级成什么
Into what?
人类的下一阶段
The next level of mankind.
我们是Ⅱ型人类
We are Human Point Two.
每个公民都能获得一次免费的升级
Every citizen will receive a free upgrade.
你们会变得像我们一样
You will become like us.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我对你们的遭遇感到很抱歉
I'm so sorry for what's been done to you.
但请听我说…
But listen to me.
这实验必须终止 今晚
This experiment ends tonight.
升级是强制性的
Upgrading is compulsory.
如果我拒绝呢
And if I refuse?
不要
Don't!.
如果我拒绝呢
What if I refuse?
我告诉你 不要
I'm telling you, don't!
如果我拒绝会发生什么
What happens if I refuse?
那你就是不兼容的
Then you are not compatible.
然后发生什么
What happens then?
你会被删除
You will be deleted.
杰琪
Jackie?
我们无能为力
There's nothing we can do.
我妈妈在里面
But my mum's in there.
她不是你妈妈 过来
She's not your mother, come on!
皮特 皮特
Pete! Pete!
皮特 这里有路出去吗
Pete, is there a way out?
侧门
The side gates.
你是谁 你怎么知道那么多的
Who are you? How do you know so much?
再过一百万年你也不会相信
You wouldn't believe it in a million years.
那是谁
Who's that?
跟在我后面
Get behind me!
天哪 看看你
Oh, my God, look at you!
我以为再也见不到你了
I thought I'd never see you again.
是的 无意冒犯 甜心
Yeah, no offense, sweetheart,
但你到底是谁
but who the hell are you?
洛斯
Rose!
他不是我
That's not me.
那是…另外一个我
That's, like, the other one.
事情还不够糟糕吗
Oh, as if things weren't bad enough,
有两个米奇
there's two Mickeys!
我是瑞奇
It's Ricky.
他们人数众多
But there's more of them.
我们被包围了
We're surrounded.
把枪放下 子弹阻挡不了他们
Put the guns down. Bullets won't stop them.
你 停止射击 马上
You! Stop shooting! Now!
我们投降
We surrender.
举起手来
Hands up.
没有必要杀死我们
There's no need to damage us.
我们是很好的原料
We're good stock.
我们志愿进行升级
We volunteer for the upgrade programme.
带我们去加工吧
Take us to be processed.
你含有叛逆成分
You are rogue elements.
但是我们投降了
But we surrender.
你们不兼容
You are incompatible.
但是我们投降了
But this is a surrender!
你会被删除
You will be deleted.
但我们投降了 听我说 我们投降了
But we're surrendering! Listen to me! We surrender!
你们是低等的
You are inferior.
人类将重生为赛博人
Man will be reborn as Cyberman
但你会被彻底毁灭
but you will perish under maximum deletion.
删除 删除 删除 删除
Delete. Delete. Delete. Delete.